<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diwakar&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diwakar&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.diwakar.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC’17 Journal: Final Phase</title>
      <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-08-21-gsoc-moodle-final-phase-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-08-21-gsoc-moodle-final-phase-copy/</guid>
      <description>Update - 6th September Project has been evaluated and approved by mentor resulting in successful GSoC completion. Extremely thankful and appreciative of Juan Leyva for the support and mentorship over last 4-5 months and entire Moodle Mobile team for regular feedback and Google for sponsoring this amazing collaboration.
Google Summer of Code 2017 Development Period is about to conclude in next few days. Final phase has started on 28th July and ends on 21st August, approximately 3 weeks, and Student Work Product Submissions are due by 29th August.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC’17 Journal: Phase 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-07-22-gsoc-moodle-phase-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-07-22-gsoc-moodle-phase-2/</guid>
      <description>With Phase 2 of GSoC&#39;17 about to end, it&amp;rsquo;s time to recapitulate the work done during this period. Phase 2 has started on 30th June and ends on 24th July, approximately 3 weeks.
Travis build optmization With increasing number of tests the Travis build is timing out (50 min hard timeout) and this became main problem. The entire Travis Build process is then reconfigured, now it uses job matrix with 7 jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC’17 Journal: Phase 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-06-28-gsoc-moodle-phase-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-06-28-gsoc-moodle-phase-1/</guid>
      <description>With Phase 1 of GSoC&#39;17 completed, it&amp;rsquo;s now time to outline the work done during this period. Phase 1 has started on 30th May and ended on 26th June, approximately 3 weeks.
Page Object Library The page object library which is used to interact with the web page and test it was outdated. It is now updated with latest protractor features like ExpectedConditions , wait, sleep etc. This helped the testing in many ways, especially, as the app totally depends on Web Services calls and heavy Ionic and Angular rendering, it takes uncertain times to load the web pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC’17 Journal: Community Bonding Period</title>
      <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-05-24-gsoc-moodle-community-bonding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-05-24-gsoc-moodle-community-bonding/</guid>
      <description>Currently in the last of week of community bonding period, it&amp;rsquo;s time to summarize everything I have done during this period. Community Bonding Period has started on 5th May and ends on 29th May, lasting approximately 3 weeks.
First Week During the first week, I was busy with my fourth semester exams and Moodle Mobile Team has also been busy with custom apps and development of critical features and improvements for v3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC&#39;17 Journal: Moodle Mobile - Project Proposal</title>
      <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-05-12-gsoc-moodle-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-05-12-gsoc-moodle-intro/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I would like to thank my GSoC mentor Juan Leyva, Moodle Mobile Team members Daniel Palou, Pau Ferrer for their continuous help and support, Moodle&amp;rsquo;s GSoC admin David Mudrak for all the guidance.
Moodle &amp;amp; Moodle Mobile Moodle is the world largest and most loved open-source Learning Management System(LMS). Moodle Mobile is the official mobile app for Moodle which brings the browser-based services of Moodle to Mobile devices across Android and iOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solarized-Dark theme configuration in Terminator</title>
      <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-01-14-solarized-dark-theme-configuration-in-terminator.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-01-14-solarized-dark-theme-configuration-in-terminator.1/</guid>
      <description>Intro Terminator is an open-source terminal emulator project with an aim to produce a useful tool for arranging terminals. You can split a window into many tabs and tabs into child terminals.
Configuration To configure your termiantor theme to solarised-dark, you need to modify the file located at ~/.config/terminator/config in your linux system.
Here is a preview of what it looks like when done:
  Now to get this theme, replace the contents of ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxy config in Bash, NPM, Bower, Atom, Git &amp; Ionic</title>
      <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-01-05-proxy-config-in-bash-npm-bower-atom-git-ionic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2017-01-05-proxy-config-in-bash-npm-bower-atom-git-ionic/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes when you are building stuff behind huge networks like universities and corporates, you often face proxy configuration issues with many applications like NPM, Bower, Ionic, Git, Atom and Linux Bash itself. This article focuses on resolving these issues.
Linux Bash With Authentication  export http_proxy=&#39;http://username:password@[Your Proxy]:[Proxy Port]/&#39; export https_proxy=&#39;http://username:password@[Your Proxy]:[Proxy Port]/&#39; export ftp_proxy=&#39;http://username:password@[Your Proxy]:[Proxy Port]/&#39; Without Authentication  export http_proxy=&#39;http://[Your Proxy]:[Proxy Port]&#39; export https_proxy=&#39;http://[Your Proxy]:[Proxy Port]&#39; export ftp_proxy=&#39;http://[Your Proxy]:[Proxy Port]&#39; View Proxy  env | grep -i proxy Remove proxy  unset http_proxy unset https_proxy unset ftp_proxy //these commands disable the proxy, temporarily for that particular bash session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to host Portfolio and Blog using GitHub Pages, HarpJS</title>
      <link>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2016-12-20-how-to-host-portfolio-and-blog-using-github-pages-harpjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.diwakar.dev/posts/2016-12-20-how-to-host-portfolio-and-blog-using-github-pages-harpjs/</guid>
      <description>When I first started Web Development, like everyone else, I also wished for an online Portfolio and super cool blog running on WordPress-like sites. But upon digging deep into it and spending some time on Web Development, I came to know about this awesome feature of GitHub, GitHub-Pages, where you can host and serve any number of static-sites for “free” with site names like username.github.io/project-name . So why not use this free feature and host a Personal portfolio and also a blog built upon HarpJS a static-site builder built upon Node that preprocesses the blog/anything just to HTML, CSS &amp;amp; JS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>